Distressed in rage after school violence
I have been a victim of school
violence and bullying.
Oppressed often, I have a lot of regrets.
My parents had to intervene to resolve
a violent episode.
During that resolution process, I began
to wonder why I always had to be a victim.
I regret being a victim all my life.
Now as a senior in high school,
I am stressed out.
Recently, when I was bullied again
(Questioner) Because I didn't want to
end up a victim and to regret that again.
(Questioner) I resorted
to attacking him back
(Questioner) But, even with that,
I ended up regretting.
(Questioner) I thought I was
paying back for all the bullying I got
(Questioner) but I felt regretful.
(Questioner) Why am I having
these feelings of regret?
We tend to explode when we have
been repressed psychologically.
In other words, repressed anger
toward one person can explode
toward another without a real due cause.
These suppressed feelings can later
explode when you get drunk,
being violent to your wife or break
things around the house.
In extreme cases, you may commit murder.
You lose all senses and
become completely irrational.
So, you had enough and decided to beat
him up. Did you beat him up a lot?
(Audience Laughter)
(Questioner) I didn't beat him.
(Questioner) I tried to stab him with a
knife but I was stopped by people around.
(Questioner) It wasn't just anyone.
(Questioner) He was the one against
whom I was holding grudges.
Regardless who it was,
or whose fault it was,
if someone gets stabbed and hurt or die,
you would end up in jail, or no?
(Questioner) Yes.
Right?
But is it really worth going to jail
because of such a guy?
(Questioner) I planned
to stab him at the time.
Because you were out of your mind.
(Questioner) Since both of
our lives are precious,
(Questioner) if I were to kill him, I
thought I would accept the consequences.
(Questioner) It's only fair
if you think about our lives.
So, you wanted to kill him
and die yourself, too, right?
That shows you were out of your mind.
You became blinded by the rage.
But honestly, is he worth
giving up your life for?
(Questioner) No.
That is a symptom of madness.
Why does that occur?
Because of the repressed anger over time.
So, the people who get drunk, throw
things around, wielding a knife,
and explode in violent behaviors
are not bad people.
They are all good people like you.
Good people.
Good people with a lot of
repressed feelings,
suddenly become
irrational and explode.
There was an incident in US, a person
killed a few people with a gun, right?
Remember the Virginia Tech incident?
Was he an evil person?
No, he wasn't.
He must have endured cruel treatments
when he was young and had repressed anger.
That anger became resentment toward
the world. Then suddenly an explosion.
But it is triggered by a small event.
In short, as I said, it's a madness,
becoming completely irrational.
So. what to do when this occurs?
When you're in junior high or high school,
are you sensible and mature or not?
(Questioner) not mature
Immature.
In that immature state, they think it
funny to have a naked girls' picture,
pass it around and giggle.
Or they brag about getting drunk,
or beating up somebody.
Or steal someone's money. These things
become some source of pride for them.
Maybe other friends would look up
to them, they think.
But in fact these are meaningless
actions, right?
But since they're young and immature,
they think these are cool.
But looking at them from an adult's
point of view, they are just silly.
just funny.
So, you don't have to get entangled
into those childish play.
But it's understandable from their
point of view.
Since they are immature.
They are not evil people;
they are but immature kids out of control.
There is no need for you to feel vengeful
if you get hit by a rock or
get kicked in the leg.
Starting today, do 108 prostrations
everyday and say, "Thank you Buddha."
"I have been foolish to hold grudges
toward immature kids' behaviors."
Then to the kids,
"I am sorry. You kids can do that."
"But I was overly sensitive
so I hated you. I am sorry.
You need to pray for repentance
toward the people you resented.
Are you able to do this?
You can repent toward them?
(Questioner) I will give it a try.
It's not about one is right
and the other is wrong.
You were too embattled and became
vengeful by their immature behaviors.
So, you ought to forgive them by saying
"I am sorry" repeatedly.
"It wasn't a big deal"
You must forgive them.
Not because they did something wrong
but because they were too immature.
So, I was wrong. What did I do wrong?
It was wrong to be vengeful.
Knowing that this was foolish, you ought
to let go of the vengeance.
Then who will become alive?
You will.
If you don't dissolve now and
continue to hold the grudges,
remember the other girl's story?
You will end up likewise.
You probably don't drink now
since you're a student.
But later when the piled up anger is
inflamed by drinks, you will lose control.
Even though you're nice normally,
but when something triggers,
you will explode.
It can't be that you become a ticking
bomb that makes people around nervous.
They won't know when you'd explode.
Then people will keep a distance.
So, please do the 108 bows,
do the prayers of repentance toward them.
Understand?
(Questioner) Yes.
I am glad you asked a question today.
(Applause)